<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Configuring Continuum</title>
    <author email="trygvis@apache.org">Trygve Laugs&#248;l</author>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Configuring Continuum">
      <p>
        The configuration file for Continuum is inside the Plexus runtime under
        <code>apps/continuum/conf/application.xml</code>.
      </p>
      <subsection name="Mail Notification">
        There are three components that is the mail notification system in Continuum:
        <ul>
          <li>
            The Mail notifier itself. There are three configurable properties:
            <ul>
              <li>
                <code>from-mailbox</code> and <code>from-name</code>: The mailbox and name that will be set as the
                <code>From</code> header for all mails sent. It's it important to ensure that the mailbox is a
                real account as a lot of SMTP server check that the mailbox actually exists before accepting the
                mail. If the from mailbox is empty or not specified the nag email address of the project will be
                used as the from mailbox.
              </li>
              <li>
                <code>timestamp-format</code>: This is the format string that is used to format the dates in the mails.
              </li>
            </ul>
          </li>
          <li>
            The recipient source. This is the component that decides who should receive the mails. The only thing
            that can be configured here is a address that will be used as the recipient for all mails sent. This
            configuration is mostly useful for people who want to make sure all mails is sent to a specific account
            during testing or development.
          </li>
          <li>
            The mail sender is the component that will send the mails to the SMTP server. The two properties that can be configured are:
            <ul>
              <li>
                <code>smtp-host</code>: The SMTP host. Make sure that this host will accept mails to and possibly
                from the addresses configured for each project.
              </li>
              <li>
                <code>smtp-port</code>: The port to use on the SMTP host.
              </li>
            </ul>
          </li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Alarm Trigger">
        <p>
          The alarm trigger will trigger a build of all the projects on a configured interval.
          <ul>
            <li>
              <code>interval</code>: The number of seconds between each round of scheduling.
            </li>
            <li>
              <code>delay</code>: The number of seconds to with with the first round of scheduling after startup.
            </li>
          </ul>
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Jetty Configuration">
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Socket Listeners">
        There are two services listening on sockets that can be configured:
        <ul>
          <li>
            <code>url-registrar-server</code>: This registrar is reading POM URLs to Maven 2 projects to build.
          </li>
          <li>
            <code>simple-socket-trigger-server</code>: This registrar is reading project IDs to schedule for build.
          </li>
        </ul>
        The only
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
