<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Configuring Continuum</title>
    <author email="trygvis@apache.org">Trygve Laugs&#248;l</author>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Installing Continuum">
      <p>
        After you have downloaded and unpacked the bundle execute <code>bin/plexus.sh</code> if you are on a UNIX
        platform or <code>bin/plexus.bat</code> if you are using Windows.
      </p>
      <p>
        After starting Continuum you can access it with your browser on
        <a href="http://localhost:8080">http://localhost:8080</a> or by using the XML-RPC interface on port 8000.
      </p>
    </section>
    <section name="Adding Projects to Continuum">
      <p>
        When adding projects note that Continuum will check out the projects directly after you press the button and
        will not return untill after the projects has been checked out either successfully or not. This is a known
        issue with Continuum and asynchronous checkouts are
        <a href="planned-features.html#Asynchronous_checkouts">planned</a>.
      </p>
      <subsection name="Adding Maven2 Projects">
        <p>
          When adding a Maven 2 project all you need is the URL to a POM. The POM has to include at least the SCM
          information to be able to check out the project.
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Adding Maven1 Projects">
        <p>
          Adding a Maven 1 it pretty much like adding a Maven 2 project, give it a URL to a POM with SCM information
          and Continuum will add the projects.
        </p>
        <p>
          There are is a caveat though: The POM cannot extend a parent POM. When Continuum is downloading the POM it
          won't know how to find the parent POMs. The best way to use Continuum with Maven 1 projects is to
          give Continuum the root POM of your projects only and then have a special goal in the root projects
          <code>maven.xml</code> to build all of the projects. In subsequent versions of Continuum we
          will deal with Maven 1.x projects in a cleaner way.
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Adding Ant Projects">
        <p>
          When adding Ant projects you have to specify the project's name, SCM URL, nag email address, version and
          the targets to execute.          
        </p>
        <p>
          NOTE: The SCM URL is a Maven SCM convention. Here's an example of
          what an SCM URL looks like: <code>scm:svn:http://svn.apache.org/repos/asf/maven/continuum/trunk</code>
        </p>        
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Adding Shell Projects">
        <p>
          When adding shell projects you have to specify the project's name, SCM URL, nag email address, version and
          the shell script to execute. The working directory of the project will be prepended to the scripts path.
        </p>
        <p>
          NOTE: The SCM URL is a Maven SCM convention. Here's an example of
          what an SCM URL looks like: <code>scm:svn:http://svn.apache.org/repos/asf/maven/continuum/trunk</code>
        </p>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section name="Building Projects">
      <subsection name="Using the Web Interface">
        <p>
          To build a project with the web interface from the project list, simply press the "build" button and the
          project will be enqueued on the build list. If Continuum isn't already building a project it will start the
          build immediately.
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Using the XML-RPC Interface">
        <p>
          By using the <code>continuum_cli.py</code> Python script you can remotely control Continuum. Start the
          script by executing <source>python continuum_cli.py</source> and write <code>help</code> to list all
          available commands.
        </p>
        <p>
          There is also a reusable Python library called <code>continuum.py</code> that can be used to integrate
          remote control over Continuum into other Python applications.
        </p>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
