<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Planned Features</title>
    <author email="trygvis@apache.org">Trygve Laugs&#248;l</author>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Planned Features for Continuum">
      <p>
        If you would like to see support for a particular feature that is not listed here please enter them in
        <a href="issue-tracking.html">JIRA</a> or send a mail to the <a href="mail-lists.html">mailing lists</a>.
      </p>
      <subsection name="Notification">
        Support for notification through these mechanisms is planned:
        <ul>
          <li><a href="http://jira.codehaus.org/browse/CONTINUUM-5">Jabber</a></li>
          <li><a href="http://jira.codehaus.org/browse/CONTINUUM-33">IRC</a></li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="SCM Support">
        <p>
          Continuum is using the Maven SCM library for checking out and getting updates from the SCM the project is
          stored in. Continuum currently only supports CVS and Subversion but support for these SCM is planned:
          <ul>
            <li>ClearCase</li>
            <li>Perforce</li>
            <li>StarTeam</li>
            <li>Visual Source Safe</li>
          </ul>
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Build Scheduling">
        Currently it only supports builds on a regular interval and Continuum definitely needs better build
        scheduling. There are two major ways to do this:
        <ul>
          <li>
            <b>Push</b>: something is triggering a build by telling Continuum to do so. Continuum already supports
            this through the socket listener that is listening for build IDs to build and through the XML-RPC server.
          </li>
          <li>
            <b>Pull</b>: Continuum is looking for changes and schedules a build when something has changed. This
            is useful for several reasons: less resources used by useless builds and it's easier to use because
            there is no need to configure your SCM to push events to Continuum.
          </li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
